Everything has a price.
The Claim is a drama, romance, western film directed by Michael Winterbottom.
A prospector sells his wife and daughter to another
gold miner for the rights to a gold mine.
Twenty years later, the prospector is a wealthy man who owns
much of the old west town named Kingdom Come.
But changes are brewing and his past is coming back to haunt him.
A surveyor and his crew scouts the town as a location for a new railroad line and a young
woman suddenly appears in the town and is evidently the man's daughter.
Daniel Dillon, played by Peter Mullan.
Lucia, played by Milla Jovovich.
Donald Dalglish, played by Wes Bentley.
Elena Burn, played by Nastassja Kinski.
Hope Burn, played by Sarah Polley.
Annie, played by Shirley Henderson.
The Claim is a 2000 Western romance film directed by Michael Winterbottom and starring
Peter Mullan, Wes Bentley, Sarah Polley, Nastassja Kinski and Milla Jovovich.
The screenplay by Frank Cottrell Boyce is loosely based on the 1886
novel The Mayor of Casterbridge by Thomas Hardy.
The original music score is composed by Michael Nyman.
The film did poorly at the box office and received mixed reviews.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book,
romance, old west, california gold rush.
The tone is emotional.